<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Timo Koch</title>
    <link>https://timokoch.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Timo Koch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:40:57 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timokoch.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Bio-fluid mechanics I am teaching a course on Bio-fluid mechanics as part of the lecture &amp;ldquo;Data-integrated Simulation Science A&amp;rdquo;, Master program Simulation Technology, at the University of Stuttgart where I am a guest lecturer (W21/22, W22/23, WS23/24).
The course integrates physiological background, mathematical modelling, numerical theory, and practical implementation of ideas in Python.
Link to lecture notes (work in progress and are continuously updated and expanded)
A Python script plotting velocity profiles for pulsating flow in a circular tube for different Womersley numbers can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>DuMux &amp;mdash; DUNE for Multi-{Phase, Component, Scale, Physics, …} flow and transport in porous media DuMux is a simulation framework with a focus on finite volume discretization methods, model coupling for multi-physics applications, and flow and transport applications in porous media.
I am one of the main developers of the open-source simulator DuMux.
Visit the DuMux website or the official DuMux GitLab repository to learn more.
Recent ideas and concepts behind DuMux are described in our recent publication: T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks, Conferences, Workshops</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/talks/</guid>
      <description>17-19 Jul 24 Lecturer and organizer, DuMux course 2024, Uni Stuttgart, Germany. 13-17 Jun 24 Speaker and minisymposium co-organizer at Interpore 2024 (International Society for Porous Media), Qingdao, China. 9-10 Apr 24 OPM (The Open Porous Media Initiative) summit Oslo, Norway. 18-20 Mar 24 Poster presentation at the SFB1313 (Collaborative Research Centre on &amp;ldquo;Interface-Driven Multi-Field Processes in Porous Media – Flow, Transport and Deformation&amp;rdquo;) Status Seminar 2024, Gültstein, Germany. 4-6 Oct 23 Keynote speaker at International Conference on Data-Integrated Simulation Science (SimTech2023), Stuttgart, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:40:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/news/</guid>
      <description>2024 10 Jan 24 Our paper &amp;ldquo;Stable and locally mass- and momentum-conservative control-volume finite-element schemes for the Stokes problem &amp;ldquo; is published in Computer Methods in Applied Mechanics and Engineering (with M. Schneider) where we developed control-volume finite element schemes for the Stokes problem. The presented approach is locally mass- and momentum-conservative schemes on unstructured grids by construction and has the simplicity of a finite volume method. PDF
2023 15 Dec 23 Our paper &amp;ldquo;Photo‐annealing of Microtissues Creates High‐Density Capillary Network Containing Living Matter in A Volumetric‐Independent Manner&amp;rdquo; is accepted for publication in Advanced Materials (with Maik Schot, Malin Becker, Carlo Alberto Paggi, Francisca Gomes, Tarek Gensheimer, Castro Johnbosco, Liebert Parreiras Nogueira, Andries van der Meer, Andreas Carlson, Håvard Haugen, Jeroen Leijten).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:40:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Research topics Research topics Embedded networks Numerics of multi-physics PDE problems Transport in brain tissue Transport in plants Reduced models for porous media Microfluidics / tissue engineering Research software engineering Embedded networks One of my ongoing research topics concerns the development of mixed-dimensional models for flow and transport processes in porous media with embedded network systems.
Many natural and technical porous media contain network structures to facilitate transport into and from these materials that usually have a low permeability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>My research can be tracked on Google scholar, Research Gate, and arXiv. I also try to keep the list below up-to-date:
Schneider, M., &amp;amp; Koch, T. (2024). Stable and locally mass- and momentum-conservative control-volume finite-element schemes for the stokes problem. Computer Methods in Applied Mechanics and Engineering https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cma.2023.116723
Busek, M., Aizenshtadt, A., Koch, T., Frank, A., Delon, L., Martinez, M. A., Golovin, A., Dumas, C., Stokowiec, J., Gruenzner, S., Melum, E.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
