<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Timo Koch</title>
    <link>https://timokoch.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Timo Koch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:40:57 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timokoch.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>DuMux &amp;mdash; DUNE for Multi-{Phase, Component, Scale, Physics, …} flow and transport in porous media I am one of the main developers of the open-source simulator DuMux.
Visit the DuMux website or the official DuMux GitLab repository to learn more.
Recent ideas and concepts behind DuMux are described in our recent publication: T. Koch, D. Gläser, K. Weishaupt et al (2021) &amp;ldquo;DuMux 3 – an open-source simulator for solving flow and transport problems in porous media with a focus on model coupling&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/talks/</guid>
      <description>Talks / conferences / workshops, etc. 2023 19-22 Jun 23 SIAM Conference on Mathematical &amp;amp; Computational Issues in the Geosciences (GS23), Bergen, Norway. 5-9 Jun 23 Large-Scale Scientific Computations 2023, Sozopol, Bulgaria. 22-25 May 23 Interpore 2023, Edinburgh, United Kingdom. 4 May 23 Speaker in the Simula SCAN seminar, Simula Research Laboratory Oslo, Norway. 25-28 Apr 23 22nd Computational Fluids Conference (CFC) in Cannes, France. 3-5 Apr 23 Lecturer and organizer, DuMux course 2023, Uni Stuttgart, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications I try to make sure my Google Scholar profile is up-to-date. Futhermore, I have a list of publications and the BibTex source file with publications that I was involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:40:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>2020-2023 &amp;ldquo;Advanced in-silico transport models for vascularized tissues with focus on the brain&amp;rdquo; (Scientia Fellows II) Perfusion magnetic resonance imaging is a time-resolved fast imaging technique based on the evaluation of how a contrast agent (CA) injected in the blood stream perfuses biological tissue (e.g. brain tissue). It is essential in the clinical workup of neurodegenerative and inflammatory diseases of the central nervous system (e.g. Alzheimer’s, multiple sclerosis) and brain cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
