<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Timo Koch</title>
    <link>https://timokoch.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Timo Koch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:40:57 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timokoch.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications  I try to make sure my Google Scholar profile is up-to-date. Futhermore, I have a list of publications and the BibTex source file with publications that I was involved.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/talks/</guid>
      <description>Talks (conferences, workshops, etc.) 2021   29 Oct 21 Tøyen Hovedgård Bio-Mechnics Workshop 2021, Oslo, Norway. 16-18 Aug 21 Lightning talk @BrainH2O, Copenhagen, Denmark (online participation) 29 Jun 21 Lecture, TU Dresden seminar applied mathematics (online) 21-24 Jun 21 SIAM Geosciences SIAM GS 2021 (online) 13-16 Jun 21 Coupled 2021 (online) 20 Jan 21 Lecture, NTNU Trondheim lecture series (online) 29 Apr 21 European Geosciences Union General Assembly EGU 2021 (online)  2020   13 Oct 20 Seminar MRI Research &amp;amp; Technology, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway 22 Sep 20 2nd Oslo Brainphatics Seminar, Simula Research Laboratory, Fornebu, Norway 26-28 Aug 20 Virtual Physiological Human VPH 2020, (online) 09-11 Mar 20 SFB1313 &amp;ldquo;Interface-Driven Multi-Field Processes in Porous Media – Flow, Transport and Deformation&amp;rdquo; Status Seminar 2020, Gültstein, Germany 02-04 Mar 20 FAU 50th anniversary applied mathematics, Erlangen, Germany 19 Feb 20 PhD defense, Stuttgart, Germany  2019   25 Nov 19 Workshop Modeling of Flow in Live Tissues, Bergen, Norway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:40:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>2020-2023 &amp;ldquo;Advanced in-silico transport models for vascularized tissues with focus on the brain&amp;rdquo; (Scientia Fellows II) Perfusion magnetic resonance imaging is a time-resolved fast imaging technique based on the evaluation of how a contrast agent (CA) injected in the blood stream perfuses biological tissue (e.g. brain tissue). It is essential in the clinical workup of neurodegenerative and inflammatory diseases of the central nervous system (e.g. Alzheimer’s, multiple sclerosis) and brain cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:40:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>DuMux &amp;mdash; DUNE for Multi-{Phase, Component, Scale, Physics, …} flow and transport in porous media I am one of the main developers of the open-source simulator DuMux.
Visit the DuMux website or the official DuMux GitLab repository to learn more.
Recent ideas and concepts behind DuMux are described in our recent publication: T. Koch, D. Gläser, K. Weishaupt et al (2021) &amp;ldquo;DuMux 3 – an open-source simulator for solving flow and transport problems in porous media with a focus on model coupling&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
