<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Timo Koch</title>
    <link>https://timokoch.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Timo Koch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:40:57 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timokoch.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Bio-fluid mechanics I am teaching a course on Bio-fluid mechanics as part of the lecture &amp;ldquo;Data-integrated Simulation Science A&amp;rdquo;, Master program Simulation Technology, at the University of Stuttgart where I am a guest lecturer (W21/22, W22/23, WS23/24).
The course integrates physiological background, mathematical modelling, numerical theory, and practical implementation of ideas in Python.
Link to lecture notes (work in progress and are continuously updated and expanded)
A Python script plotting velocity profiles for pulsating flow in a circular tube for different Womersley numbers can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>DuMux &amp;mdash; DUNE for Multi-{Phase, Component, Scale, Physics, …} flow and transport in porous media DuMux is a simulation framework with a focus on finite volume discretization methods, model coupling for multi-physics applications, and flow and transport applications in porous media.
I am one of the main developers of the open-source simulator DuMux.
Visit the DuMux website or the official DuMux GitLab repository to learn more.
Recent ideas and concepts behind DuMux are described in our recent publication: T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/talks/</guid>
      <description>4-6 Oct 23 Keynote speaker at International Conference on Data-Integrated Simulation Science (SimTech2023), Stuttgart, Germany. Link to abstract. 17-19 Sep 23 Speaker at the Dune user and developer meeeing, Dresden, Germany. 19-22 Jun 23 Speaker at SIAM Conference on Mathematical &amp;amp; Computational Issues in the Geosciences (GS23), Bergen, Norway. 5-9 Jun 23 LSpeaker at arge-Scale Scientific Computations 2023, Sozopol, Bulgaria. 22-25 May 23 Speaker at Interpore 2023, Edinburgh, United Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:40:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/news/</guid>
      <description>2023 4 Sep 23 We published a new preprint on the ArXiv &amp;ldquo;Stable and locally mass- and momentum-conservative control-volume finite-element schemes for the Stokes problem &amp;ldquo; (with M. Schneider) where we developed control-volume finite element schemes for the Stokes problem. The presented approach yields a locally mass- and momentum-conservative schemes on unstructured grids by construction and has the simplicity of a finite volume method. PDF
03 Jun 23 Our paper &amp;ldquo;Collaborative benchmarking of functional-structural root architecture models: Quantitative comparison of simulated root water uptake&amp;rdquo; is published in in silico Plants (benchmark effort involving five different groups led by Andrea Schnepf).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:40:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Research topics Research topics Embedded networks Transport in brain tissue Transport in plants Numerics of multi-physics problems Reduced models for porous media Microfluidics / tissue engineering Research software engineering Embedded networks One of my ongoing research topics concerns the development of mixed-dimensional models for flow and transport processes in porous media with embedded network systems.
Many natural and technical porous media contain network structures to facilitate transport into and from these materials that usually have a low permeability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://timokoch.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timokoch.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>My research can be tracked on Google scholar, Research Gate, and arXiv. I also try to keep to list below up-to-date:
Busek, M., Aizenshtadt, A., Koch, T., Frank, A., Delon, L., Martinez, M. A., Golovin, A., Dumas, C., Stokowiec, J., Gruenzner, S., Melum, E., &amp;amp; Krauss, S. (2023). Pump-less, recirculating organ-on-a-chip (rOoC) platform. Lab on a Chip, 23(4), 591–608. https://doi.org/10.1039/d2lc00919f
Gläser, D., Koch, T., Peters, S., Marcus, S., &amp;amp; Flemisch, B.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
